<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Master RSS Feed</title><link>https://yourrepo.github.io/master_feed.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed</description><item><title>BioAge Labs Begins Phase 1 Trial of Oral NLRP3 Inhibitor for Obesity</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1348-bioage-labs-begins-phase-1-trial-of-oral-nlrp3-inhibitor-for-obesity/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://bioagelabs.com/">BioAge Labs</a> <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/08/15/3134242/0/en/BioAge-Labs-Announces-First-Participant-Dosed-in-Phase-1-Clinical-Trial-of-BGE-102-a-Novel-Brain-Penetrant-NLRP3-Inhibitor.html">has started</a> human testing of <strong>BGE-102</strong>, an orally available <strong>NLRP3</strong> inhibitor designed to cross the blood-brain barrier. The Phase 1 trial will evaluate safety, dosing, and biological activity, with early results expected by the end of 2025. The compound is initially being developed for obesity, after showing weight-loss effects in preclinical studies both alone and in combination with GLP-1 receptor agonists.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI Designs Novel Antibiotics Against MRSA and Drug-Resistant Gonorrhea</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1349-generative-ai-designs-novel-antibiotics-against-mrsa-and-drug-resistant-gonorrhea/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Researchers at MIT and the Broad Institute <a href="http://www.cell.com/cell/abstract/S0092-8674(25)00855-4">have reported</a> generative artificial intelligence systems capable of designing entirely new antibiotics, including a compound active against methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). The study, <a href="https://www.cell.com/cell/abstract/S0092-8674(25)00855-4">published August 14 in Cell</a>, describes two lead molecules&mdash;<strong>NG1</strong> and <strong>DN1</strong>&mdash;produced by deep learning models trained on a dataset of ~40,000 small molecules with known antibacterial profiles.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Owkin to Bring Agentic AI into Vienna’s Oncology Ecosystem</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1350-owkin-to-bring-agentic-ai-into-viennas-oncology-ecosystem/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.owkin.com/newsfeed/owkin-and-the-comprehensive-cancer-center-of-the-medical-university-of-vienna-announce-strategic-collaboration-to-accelerate-cancer-research-and-care-with-ai-copilot">Owkin</a> and the <a href="https://ccc.meduniwien.ac.at/en/">Comprehensive Cancer Center of the Medical University of Vienna</a> <a href="https://www.owkin.com/newsfeed/owkin-and-the-comprehensive-cancer-center-of-the-medical-university-of-vienna-announce-strategic-collaboration-to-accelerate-cancer-research-and-care-with-ai-copilot">have entered</a> a collaboration to deploy agentic AI tools in oncology research and care. The partnership will introduce <strong>Owkin&rsquo;s AI copilot</strong>, <a href="https://k.owkin.com/auth/signin?next=%2Fchat">Owkin K</a>, into Vienna&rsquo;s oncology ecosystem, with a first focus on advanced bladder cancer. The system will be refined through feedback from clinicians and researchers, aiming to support biological reasoning, precision medicine, and therapeutic strategy development.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley’s Molecular Devices Brings AI to Brain Organoid Culture</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1351-silicon-valleys-molecular-devices-brings-ai-to-brain-organoid-culture/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.biopharmatrend.com/m/company/molecular-devices/">Molecular Devices</a> <a href="https://www.moleculardevices.com/newsroom/news/brain-organoid-culture-with-incubation-accelerating-neurodegenerative-disease-research">has released</a> an upgrade to its <strong><a href="http://cellxpress.ai">CellXpress.ai</a> Automated Cell Culture System</strong>, adding rocking incubation and AI-driven workflow automation for brain organoid culture. The feature is designed to reduce the high manual workload of organoid maintenance and to support long-term, reproducible experiments for neurodegenerative disease research.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ginkgo, Inductive Bio, and Tangible Scientific Connect AI Models with Automated Labs for Drug Discovery</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1352-ginkgo-inductive-bio-and-tangible-scientific-connect-ai-models-with-automated-labs-for-drug-discovery/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://datapoints.ginkgo.bio/what-we-do/small-molecule">Ginkgo Bioworks&rsquo; Datapoints unit</a>, <a href="https://www.inductive.bio/">Inductive Bio</a>, and <a href="https://tangiblescientific.com/sample-management">Tangible Scientific</a> <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ginkgo-datapoints-tangible-scientific-and-inductive-bio-partner-to-deploy-ai-driven-lab-in-the-loop-workflows-across-the-biopharma-industry-302533834.html">have partnered</a> to deliver a lab-in-the-loop workflow that ties AI-driven molecular design directly to experimental validation. The collaboration integrates predictive ADMET modeling, automated compound logistics, and rapid assay services, with the aim of reducing cycle times in small molecule drug discovery.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI Is Transforming Medicinal Chemistry Between Discovery and Manufacture</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1353-how-ai-is-transforming-medicinal-chemistry-between-discovery-and-manufacture/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>In medicinal chemistry, the &ldquo;make&rdquo; stage of the design&ndash;make&ndash;test&ndash;analyze (DMTA) cycle is often where good ideas go to die. Synthetic bottlenecks, expensive building blocks, low-yield reactions, and complications during scale-up for manufacturing can turn promising drug candidates into abandoned projects.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Innovatrix and Opyl Partner to Launch AI-Driven Insurance for Clinical Trial Failure</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1354-innovatrix-and-opyl-partner-to-launch-ai-driven-insurance-for-clinical-trial-failure/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://innovatrixcap.co.uk/">Innovatrix Capital</a> has partnered with <a href="https://opyl.ai/">Opyl Limited&rsquo;s</a> <a href="https://trialkey.ai/">TrialKey</a> platform to embed predictive analytics into parametric insurance products designed to cover the financial risk of clinical trial failure. The approach combines risk transfer mechanisms with outcome probability modelling in an attempt to address the heavy capital exposure that accompanies drug development.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>KYORIN Pharmaceutical Adopts AI Drug Discovery Platform From Elix</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1355-kyorin-pharmaceutical-adopts-ai-drug-discovery-platform-from-elix/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.kyorin-pharm.co.jp/en/">KYORIN Pharmaceutical</a> <a href="https://www.einpresswire.com/article/837644906/elix-provides-ai-drug-discovery-platform-elix-discovery-to-kyorin-pharmaceutical">has adopted</a> <a href="https://www.elix-inc.com/platform/">Elix Discovery</a>, an AI-based drug discovery platform developed by Tokyo-based <a href="https://www.elix-inc.com/">Elix</a>. The system is designed to accelerate early-stage research by applying machine learning to compound profiling, molecular generation, and predictive modeling.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunai Opens Free Single-Cell Sequencing Program for Academic Labs</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1356-immunai-opens-free-single-cell-sequencing-program-for-academic-labs/</link><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://immunai">Immunai</a>, a New York&ndash;based company specializing in AI-driven immune system mapping, <a href="https://www.immunai.com/collaboration/">has announced</a> a program offering academic researchers free access to its single-cell immune profiling platform, covering transcriptomic, surface proteomic, and TCR sequencing for studies of up to 1,000 human samples. The initiative is aimed at groups studying cancer, autoimmunity, and immunotherapy, as well as other immune-related areas, and is intended to offset reduced access to research infrastructure caused by tightening federal funding.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Potential Breakthrough in Cell Reprogramming as OpenAI and Retro Biosciences Report 50x Pluripotency Marker Expression Gains</title><link>https://www.biopharmatrend.com/post/1357-potential-breakthrough-in-cell-reprogramming-as-openai-and-retro-biosciences-report-50x-pluripotency-marker-expression-gains/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI and Retro Biosciences <a href="https://openai.com/index/accelerating-life-sciences-research-with-retro-biosciences" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">have released new findings</a> from a joint effort in AI-driven protein engineering. Using GPT-4b micro, a biology-specialized variant of GPT-4o, the team designed two modified versions of Yamanaka factors, RetroSOX and RetroKLF, that showed over 50-fold increases in pluripotency marker expression and improved DNA repair activity during cell reprogramming.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/fda-will-fully-adopt-generative-ai-end-june-makary-says&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;FDA will fully adopt generative AI by end of June, Martin Makary says&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/fda-will-fully-adopt-generative-ai-end-june-makary-says</link><description><![CDATA[The Food and Drug Administration is going all in on artificial intelligence. Commissioner Martin Makary, M.D., has instructed all the agency’s centers to fully integrate generative AI into their work by the end of June.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/labcorp-cro-spinout-fortrea-says-farewell-inaugural-ceo&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Labcorp CRO spinout Fortrea says farewell to inaugural CEO as stock declines further&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/labcorp-cro-spinout-fortrea-says-farewell-inaugural-ceo</link><description><![CDATA[North Carolina-based CRO Fortrea is saying goodbye to its CEO. Thomas Pike is hitting the road effective May 13 and will be replaced in the interim by Peter Neupert, Fortrea’s lead independent director.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/julius-clinical-and-peachtree-bioresearch-blossom-cns-focused-global-cro-merger&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Julius Clinical and Peachtree BioResearch blossom into CNS-focused global CRO&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/julius-clinical-and-peachtree-bioresearch-blossom-cns-focused-global-cro-merger</link><description><![CDATA[Netherlands-based Julius Clinical and U.S.-based Peachtree BioResearch Solutions are joining forces to create a global CNS-focused CRO.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/clinical-trial-diversity-non-profit-launches-board-fda-and-big-pharma-vets&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Clinical trial diversity nonprofit launches with FDA, Big Pharma vets on its board&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/clinical-trial-diversity-non-profit-launches-board-fda-and-big-pharma-vets</link><description><![CDATA[After a two-year pilot period, Equitable Breakthroughs in Medicine Development has officially launched a nonprofit meant to expand access to clinical trials.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/abbvie-taps-oncology-research-institute-aid-running-diverse-cancer-trials&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;AbbVie taps oncology research institute for aid running diverse cancer trials&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/abbvie-taps-oncology-research-institute-aid-running-diverse-cancer-trials</link><description><![CDATA[AbbVie is looking south to boost its community-based clinical trials. The Chicago-area pharma giant is partnering with Nashville-based Sarah Cannon Research Institute to run diverse trials for AbbVie’s novel cancer candidates.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/asco-uneven-us-clinical-trial-spread-leaves-millions-women-without-access-breast-cancer-studies&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;ASCO: Uneven US clinical trial spread leaves millions of women without access to breast cancer studies&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/asco-uneven-us-clinical-trial-spread-leaves-millions-women-without-access-breast-cancer-studies</link><description><![CDATA[Black women remain underrepresented in clinical trials for triple negative breast cancer, but distance to the sites may not be the main reason.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/asco-medidata-and-medable-debut-new-digital-tools-trial-prediction-and-follow&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;ASCO: Medidata and Medable debut new digital trial tools&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/asco-medidata-and-medable-debut-new-digital-tools-trial-prediction-and-follow</link><description><![CDATA[The clinical trial tech companies Medidata and Medable are both taking to the floor of the American Society of Clinical Oncology Annual Meeting in Chicago to spread the word about new offerings.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/oncology-research-institute-unites-cro-and-site-management-operations-veevas-clinical-platform&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Oncology research group unites CRO, site management operations with Veeva&apos;s clinical platform&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/oncology-research-institute-unites-cro-and-site-management-operations-veevas-clinical-platform</link><description><![CDATA[Cancer clinical trial specialist Sarah Cannon Research Institute is unifying its site management and contract research organizations on a single platform, with the Nashville, Tennessee-based company adopting Veeva Systems’ clinical platform.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/uk-professional-organizations-call-actions-improve-diverse-participation-clinical-trials&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;UK professional organizations call for actions to improve diverse participation in clinical trials&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/uk-professional-organizations-call-actions-improve-diverse-participation-clinical-trials</link><description><![CDATA[A pair of professional organizations in the U.K. is calling for the biopharma industry and national government to take action to improve diversity in clinical trials. The call comes after the Association of the British Pharmaceutical Industry and the Association of Medical Research Charities held an event with industry stakeholders to identify barriers to increasing diversity in clinical research.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/headlands-researchs-network-expands-puerto-rico-san-juan-site-acquisition&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Headlands Research expands to Puerto Rico with CMRCenter acquisition&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/headlands-researchs-network-expands-puerto-rico-san-juan-site-acquisition</link><description><![CDATA[Headlands Research, a clinical trial site network with locations across the U.S. and Canada, has made its first step into the Caribbean.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/cro-veeda-picks-mangos-generative-ai-platform-clinical-trials&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;CRO Veeda picks Mango’s generative AI platform for clinical trials&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/cro-veeda-picks-mangos-generative-ai-platform-clinical-trials</link><description><![CDATA[Newly rebranded Indian CRO Veeda Lifesciences has invested in Boston health tech firm Mango Sciences, giving Veeda access to the fruit of Mango’s generative AI labors.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/evestia-clinical-and-atlantic-research-group-merge-form-global-cro&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Evestia Clinical and Atlantic Research Group merge to form global CRO&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/evestia-clinical-and-atlantic-research-group-merge-form-global-cro</link><description><![CDATA[A pair of CROs from opposite sides of the Atlantic Ocean are merging to form a global organization. Evestia Clinical and Atlantic Research Group are joining forces to bring clients expertise in oncology, immunology, neurology and late-stage clinical trials, according to a July 15 release.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/korean-cro-corestemchemon-inks-collaboration-expand-organoids-and-transcriptomics&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Korean CRO CorestemChemon inks collaboration to expand into organoids and transcriptomics&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/korean-cro-corestemchemon-inks-collaboration-expand-organoids-and-transcriptomics</link><description><![CDATA[Korean preclinical CRO CorestemChemon is expanding its offerings through a partnership with ATG Lifetech with the goal of bringing pharma clients next-gen nonclinical solutions.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/roches-flatiron-health-announces-tripling-cancer-network-size-across-uk-germany-and-japan&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Roche&apos;s Flatiron Health triples cancer network size across UK, Germany and Japan&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/roches-flatiron-health-announces-tripling-cancer-network-size-across-uk-germany-and-japan</link><description><![CDATA[Roche’s Flatiron Health is celebrating a milestone. Over the last year, the company has tripled the size of its international oncology network across the U.K., Germany and Japan.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/nextstage-brings-experienced-clinical-research-leader-take-operations-spotlight&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;NextStage brings on experienced clinical research leader to take operations spotlight&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/nextstage-brings-experienced-clinical-research-leader-take-operations-spotlight</link><description><![CDATA[Veteran clinical research leader Melissa Holbrook has found her next permanent role. The trained nurse practitioner has assumed the chief operating officer mantle at NextStage Clinical Research, her first time taking a seat in the C-suite.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/backed-big-pharma-nih-foundation-launches-program-get-animal-testing-alternatives-across&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Backed by Big Pharma, NIH foundation launches program to push animal testing alternatives across regulatory finish line&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/backed-big-pharma-nih-foundation-launches-program-get-animal-testing-alternatives-across</link><description><![CDATA[As the fervor around ending animal testing in drug development has grown since President Donald Trump started his second term, a group of nonprofits, corporations and regulators has been meeting to discuss plans for creating alternative methods. Now, it's ready to invest in the most promising projects.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/charles-river-collaboration-aims-bring-crowdfunding-early-stage-cell-and-gene-biotechs&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Charles River collaboration aims to bring crowdfunding to early-stage cell and gene biotechs&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/charles-river-collaboration-aims-bring-crowdfunding-early-stage-cell-and-gene-biotechs</link><description><![CDATA[After launching an expanded incubator for early-stage biotechs late last year, Charles River Laboratories is now looking to give participants access to crowdsourced cash. The CRO is working to secure a collaboration with BioTech Social to grant incubator companies entry into the latter’s crowdfunding portal.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/west-virginia-university-cancer-institute-finds-place-it-belongs-ryght-ai-site-network&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;West Virginia University Cancer Institute finds place it belongs in Ryght AI site network&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/west-virginia-university-cancer-institute-finds-place-it-belongs-ryght-ai-site-network</link><description><![CDATA[Ryght AI traveled down country roads to find the newest member of its growing clinical trial site collection. West Virginia University Cancer Institute has joined the health tech company’s research network, gaining access to an AI platform and a suite of fellow network members to collaborate with.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/medidata-elevates-amgen-vet-moneymaker-lead-business-strategy&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Medidata elevates Amgen vet Lisa Moneymaker to lead business strategy&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/medidata-elevates-amgen-vet-moneymaker-lead-business-strategy</link><description><![CDATA[Clinical trial tech outfit Medidata has elevated a new strategy leader from within. Industry veteran Lisa Moneymaker will now guide the company’s future vision as chief strategy officer, Medidata announced on Aug. 13.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/private-equity-firm-acquires-clinical-trial-site-network-headlands-research&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Private equity firm acquires clinical trial site network Headlands Research&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/private-equity-firm-acquires-clinical-trial-site-network-headlands-research</link><description><![CDATA[After years of striking acquisitions to build up its site network, Headlands Research has now been bought itself. Headlands has been scooped up by private equity firm THL Partners, which entered an agreement to buy the clinical trial company from founding firm KKR.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/fda-recommends-all-cancer-clinical-trials-collect-overall-survival-data&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;FDA draft recommends overall survival data collection for all cancer trials&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/fda-recommends-all-cancer-clinical-trials-collect-overall-survival-data</link><description><![CDATA[More than two years after the FDA held a public workshop on measuring overall survival in cancer clinical trials, the agency has released a draft guidance on the topic, recommending that OS be used as a primary endpoint whenever feasible.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/iqvia-and-veeva-go-enemies-friends-ending-legal-spat-and-forming-long-term-pact&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;IQVIA and Veeva go from adversaries to friends, ending legal spat and forming long-term pact&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/iqvia-and-veeva-go-enemies-friends-ending-legal-spat-and-forming-long-term-pact</link><description><![CDATA[The yearslong legal kerfuffle between IQVIA and Veeva Systems has come to a close, with the former adversaries setting aside their differences to launch a series of clinical and commercial partnerships.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/chinese-cro-chempartner-announces-new-boston-research-facility&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Chinese CRO ChemPartner gets ready to debut new Boston research facility&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/chinese-cro-chempartner-announces-new-boston-research-facility</link><description><![CDATA[Chinese contract research and manufacturing outfit ChemPartner is building out its U.S. footprint in the heart of the bustling Boston biotech scene. The company’s new Boston Center of Excellence is set to open in Watertown, Massachusetts, on Sept. 10, ChemPartner announced in an Aug. 20 release.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/amgen-looks-level-clinical-trials-veeva-systems-partnership&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Amgen looks to level up clinical trials with Veeva Systems partnership&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/amgen-looks-level-clinical-trials-veeva-systems-partnership</link><description><![CDATA[Veeva Systems has unveiled its first big biotech pact since thawing relations with one-time adversary IQVIA, teaming up with Amgen to find ways to improve clinical trial processes.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/cro/australian-biotech-filamon-partners-pi-health-anti-inflammatory-cancer-trial&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Australian biotech Filamon partners with Pi Health for anti-inflammatory cancer trial&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/cro/australian-biotech-filamon-partners-pi-health-anti-inflammatory-cancer-trial</link><description><![CDATA[Global CRO Pi Health has pulled a new partnership out of the oven. Building on a growing presence Down Under, Pi Health will provide CRO services and a clinical trial software platform to Australian biotech Filamon.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/philips-invest-150m-us-manufacturing-base-including-ultrasound-site-expansion&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Philips to invest $150M in US manufacturing base, including ultrasound site expansion&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/philips-invest-150m-us-manufacturing-base-including-ultrasound-site-expansion</link><description><![CDATA[Philips is planning to invest at least $150 million in new funding for its U.S. production base, including through the expansion of a Pennsylvania facility for hospital ultrasound hardware.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/baxters-novum-iq-corrections-grow-scope-include-syringe-pumps&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Baxter&apos;s Novum IQ corrections grow in scope to include syringe pumps&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/baxters-novum-iq-corrections-grow-scope-include-syringe-pumps</link><description><![CDATA[Last month, Baxter and the FDA highlighted a problem with the Novum IQ large-volume pump, tied to 79 serious injuries and two deaths. Now, separate software issues are affecting both the large-volume system as well as its syringe-based pump.<br>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/new-blood-pressure-treatment-guidelines-add-recommendations-renal-denervation&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;New blood pressure treatment guidelines add recommendations for renal denervation&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/new-blood-pressure-treatment-guidelines-add-recommendations-renal-denervation</link><description><![CDATA[The American Heart Association and the American College of Cardiology updated their 2017 hypertension guidelines, including renal denervation for the first time.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/nighttime-insulin-patch-pump-maker-luna-diabetes-raises-236m&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Nighttime insulin patch pump maker Luna Diabetes raises $23.6M&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/nighttime-insulin-patch-pump-maker-luna-diabetes-raises-236m</link><description><![CDATA[Luna Diabetes aims to overcome the limitations of insulin pens and multiple daily injections, by offering an overnight patch pump that people can wear while they sleep.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/medtronic-expands-board-chase-ma-efficiencies-activist-investor-takes-stake&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Medtronic expands board to chase M&amp;A, efficiencies as activist investor takes stake&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/medtronic-expands-board-chase-ma-efficiencies-activist-investor-takes-stake</link><description><![CDATA[The company’s newest stakeholder, Elliott Investment Management, said it has become one of Medtronic's largest investors.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/fda-clears-signos-over-counter-cgm-powered-weight-loss-app&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;FDA clears Signos&apos; over-the-counter, CGM-powered weight loss app&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/fda-clears-signos-over-counter-cgm-powered-weight-loss-app</link><description><![CDATA[Signos' system employs Dexcom's Stelo CGM and pairs it with an app to track how food choices, activity, stress and sleep can all affect metabolism.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/iantrek-sees-42m-fundraising-alternative-glaucoma-surgery-launch&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Iantrek sees $42M fundraising for alternative glaucoma surgery launch&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/iantrek-sees-42m-fundraising-alternative-glaucoma-surgery-launch</link><description><![CDATA[Iantrek’s AlloFlo Uveo system is designed to offer ophthalmic surgeons another route to drain fluids from the eye, using a porous, biologic material.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/masimo-sues-us-customs-over-apple-watch-blood-oxygen-green-light&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Masimo sues US Customs over Apple Watch blood oxygen green light&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/masimo-sues-us-customs-over-apple-watch-blood-oxygen-green-light</link><description><![CDATA[Masimo is taking the U.S. government to court over its decision to allow blood oxygen tracking to return to the Apple Watch, saying its decision was unlawful and that Apple’s workaround still infringes its sensor patents.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/thermo-fisher-opens-automated-lab-tools-plant-north-carolina&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Thermo Fisher opens automated lab tools plant in N.C.&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/thermo-fisher-opens-automated-lab-tools-plant-north-carolina</link><description><![CDATA[The site in Mebane, between Durham and Greensboro, can churn out 96 pipette tips every 12 seconds as well as 5,000 finished assemblies every hour.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/tempus-claims-ai-pathology-developer-paige-81m-deal&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Tempus claims AI pathology developer Paige in $81M deal&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/tempus-claims-ai-pathology-developer-paige-81m-deal</link><description><![CDATA[Tempus bought the former Fierce 15 winner in part for its spanning nearly 7 million digitized pathology slides and clinical data from Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/terumo-inks-15b-deal-liver-transplant-tech-developer-organox&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Terumo inks $1.5B deal for liver transplant tech developer OrganOx&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/terumo-inks-15b-deal-liver-transplant-tech-developer-organox</link><description><![CDATA[The deal would mark the Japanese devicemaker’s entry into the organ transplant sector, with OrganOx’s metra platform providing tissue perfusion during transport.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/abbotts-absorbable-below-knee-stent-nets-european-approval-peripheral-artery-disease&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Abbott&apos;s absorbable, below-the-knee stent nets European approval in peripheral artery disease&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/abbotts-absorbable-below-knee-stent-nets-european-approval-peripheral-artery-disease</link><description><![CDATA[Abbott said the CE mark opens up the Esprit BTK scaffold to more than 50 million people on the continent—about twice the population in the U.S.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/proverum-raises-80m-stent-treatment-aimed-enlarged-prostates&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;ProVerum raises $80M for stent aimed at enlarged prostates&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/proverum-raises-80m-stent-treatment-aimed-enlarged-prostates</link><description><![CDATA[The Dublin-based company’s ProVee system is designed to hold open an obstructed urethra using a low-profile, nitinol frame.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/philips-rolls-out-major-ai-upgrades-cardiac-ultrasound-platforms&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Philips rolls out major AI upgrades for cardiac ultrasound platforms&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/philips-rolls-out-major-ai-upgrades-cardiac-ultrasound-platforms</link><description><![CDATA[Transcend Plus, for Philips' EPIQ and Affiniti CVx echo systems, includes 2D and 3D applications that automatically calculate measures related to heart failure, valve disease and other conditions.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/3d-printed-orthopedic-implant-maker-restor3d-raises-104m&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;3D-printed orthopedic implant maker restor3d raises $104M&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/3d-printed-orthopedic-implant-maker-restor3d-raises-104m</link><description><![CDATA[That includes $65 million in a new equity investment from Partners Group, netting the firm a significant minority stake.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/fda-flags-issues-review-telixs-pet-diagnostic-agent-kidney-cancer&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;FDA flags issues in review of Telix&apos;s PET diagnostic agent for kidney cancer&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/fda-flags-issues-review-telixs-pet-diagnostic-agent-kidney-cancer</link><description><![CDATA[The FDA has asked Telix for more information about the manufacturing of its novel PET agent for clear-cell renal cell carcinoma.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/esc-2025-new-heart-valve-guidelines-call-earlier-tavr&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;At ESC 2025, new heart valve guidelines call for earlier TAVR as implant makers expand reach&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/esc-2025-new-heart-valve-guidelines-call-earlier-tavr</link><description><![CDATA[The latest updates since 2021 are based on what the medical groups describe as “an exponential increase in medical knowledge about valvular heart disease,” and as TAVR outpaces surgical procedures on the continent.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/medtronic-scores-insulin-pump-clearance-type-2-diabetes-preps-launch-abbott-instinct-cgm&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Medtronic scores insulin pump approval in Type 2 diabetes, preps launch of Abbott Instinct CGM&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/medtronic-scores-insulin-pump-clearance-type-2-diabetes-preps-launch-abbott-instinct-cgm</link><description><![CDATA[Medtronic's MiniMed 780G automated insulin pump is opening up to adults with Type 2 diabetes, alongside the launch of a new continuous glucose sensor made specially by Abbott.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/johnson-johnson-delivers-10-year-impella-gains-severe-heart-attacks&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Johnson &amp; Johnson delivers 10-year Impella gains in severe heart attacks&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/johnson-johnson-delivers-10-year-impella-gains-severe-heart-attacks</link><description><![CDATA[Johnson &amp; Johnson MedTech demonstrated that its Impella CP can help STEMI heart attack patients gain an additional 600 days of life, on average.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/kardium-grabs-fda-approval-globe-pulsed-field-ablation-catheter-afib&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Kardium grabs FDA approval for Globe pulsed field ablation catheter in afib&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/kardium-grabs-fda-approval-globe-pulsed-field-ablation-catheter-afib</link><description><![CDATA[Kardium has gotten the go-ahead to compete in the emerging sector against heavyweights such as Boston Scientific, Medtronic and Johnson &amp; Johnson.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/illumina-begins-rolling-out-protein-prep-platform-ahead-somalogic-buy&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Illumina begins rolling out protein prep platform ahead of SomaLogic buy&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/illumina-begins-rolling-out-protein-prep-platform-ahead-somalogic-buy</link><description><![CDATA[The ink isn't dry on Illumina's $425 million deal to acquire SomaLogic, but the two companies are moving forward with the proteomics platform they've been developing together for years.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/quest-diagnostics-launches-new-pharmacogenomics-testing-program&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Quest Diagnostics launches new pharmacogenomics testing program&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/quest-diagnostics-launches-new-pharmacogenomics-testing-program</link><description><![CDATA[Quest said its test will span drugs used across psychiatry, neurology, cardiology, oncology, rheumatology and pain management, as well as for transplant recipients.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/galvanize-therapeutics-nets-100m-and-new-ceo-bring-pulsed-field-ablation-lung-cancer&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Galvanize Therapeutics nets $100M, and a new CEO, to bring pulsed field ablation to lung cancer&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/galvanize-therapeutics-nets-100m-and-new-ceo-bring-pulsed-field-ablation-lung-cancer</link><description><![CDATA[The company has named its chairman, Doug Godshall, as CEO amid a $100 million series C venture capital fundraising.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/medtronics-hugo-robot-logs-success-hernia-repair-trial&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Medtronic’s Hugo robot logs success in hernia repair trial&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/medtronics-hugo-robot-logs-success-hernia-repair-trial</link><description><![CDATA[While its Hugo surgical robot undergoes FDA review, Medtronic presented clinical data demonstrating success in inguinal and ventral hernia repairs.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/medtech/senseonics-retake-eversense-cgm-commercial-control-ascensia-diabetes-care&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Senseonics to retake Eversense CGM commercial control from Ascensia Diabetes Care&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/medtech/senseonics-retake-eversense-cgm-commercial-control-ascensia-diabetes-care</link><description><![CDATA[Senseonics aims to speed up the commercial rollout of its latest, yearlong CGM sensor implant, the Eversense 365.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/vertex-forges-2b-alliance-enlaza-create-new-autoimmune-drugs-improve-conditioning-methods&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Vertex forges $2B-plus alliance with Enlaza to create new autoimmune drugs, improve conditioning methods&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/vertex-forges-2b-alliance-enlaza-create-new-autoimmune-drugs-improve-conditioning-methods</link><description><![CDATA[Vertex Pharmaceuticals is offering Enlaza Therapeutics more than $2 billion in biobucks through a multitarget drug discovery deal aiming to create new T-cell engagers and small-format drug conjugates.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/zenas-biopharma-bestowed-300m-royalty-get-autoimmune-asset-across-fda-finish-line&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Royalty bestows Zenas with $300M deal to push autoimmune asset across FDA finish line&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/zenas-biopharma-bestowed-300m-royalty-get-autoimmune-asset-across-fda-finish-line</link><description><![CDATA[Zenas BioPharma has secured up to $300 million from Royalty Pharma in return for royalties on sales of lead autoimmune candidate obexelimab. The cash is intended to help Zenas get its star asset across the phase 3 finish line in IgG4-related disease and into commercialization, the companies announced in a Sept. 2 release.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/amgen-build-600m-rd-site-hire-hundreds-california&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Amgen to build $600M R&amp;D site, hire hundreds in California &lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/amgen-build-600m-rd-site-hire-hundreds-california</link><description><![CDATA[Amgen is putting down $600 million to build a new R&amp;D site in California, a move the Big Pharma says will create hundreds of U.S. jobs.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/after-strategic-pivot-editas-lays-out-plan-target-high-cholesterol-gene-editing&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;After strategic pivot, Editas lays out plan to target high cholesterol with gene editing&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/after-strategic-pivot-editas-lays-out-plan-target-high-cholesterol-gene-editing</link><description><![CDATA[In the next milestone in Editas' strategic pivot, the company revealed its new lead program as a possible one-time treatment for high cholesterol.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/analysts-rave-and-stock-soars-cytokinetics-shares-detailed-phase-3-data-potential-cardio&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;As Cytokinetics awaits FDA approval decision, phase 3 cardio win sends stock soaring&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/analysts-rave-and-stock-soars-cytokinetics-shares-detailed-phase-3-data-potential-cardio</link><description><![CDATA[Cytokinetics spent Labor Day weekend in Spain, sharing a big phase 3 win for its lead cardio candidate at the European Society of Cardiology Congress in Madrid. A daily pill of small molecule aficamten improved oxygen capacity by 1.1 milliliters per kilogram per minute in patients with genetic heart enlargement, easily besting the 1.2-point loss in patients given a standard-of-care beta blocker, the biotech announced in an Aug. 30 release.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/boston-biotech-radiance-offers-china-biopharma-1b-plus-rights-next-gen-adc&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Boston biotech Radiance offers China firm $1B-plus for rights to next-gen ADC&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/boston-biotech-radiance-offers-china-biopharma-1b-plus-rights-next-gen-adc</link><description><![CDATA[Boston-based Radiance Biopharma is doling out $15 million in cash and offering more than $1 billion in milestones for licensing rights to a bispecific antibody-drug conjugate from a Chinese drug developer.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/servier-shells-out-210m-upfront-license-ideayas-potential-first-class-pkc-inhibitor-outside&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Servier shells out $210M upfront to license Ideaya&apos;s potential first-in-class PKC inhibitor outside the US&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/servier-shells-out-210m-upfront-license-ideayas-potential-first-class-pkc-inhibitor-outside</link><description><![CDATA[After throwing down $70 million upfront to partner on Black Diamond Therapeutics’ solid tumor candidate earlier this year, Servier is pulling out its checkbook to ink yet another oncology licensing deal.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/novartis-returns-argo-multi-faceted-5b-cardiovascular-collab&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Novartis returns to Argo for multifaceted $5B cardiovascular collab&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/novartis-returns-argo-multi-faceted-5b-cardiovascular-collab</link><description><![CDATA[Novartis has returned to Argo Biopharmaceutical with $160 million in upfront cash to explore various cardiovascular meds in the Chinese biotech’s siRNA pipeline.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/pfizer-valneva-boosted-updated-vaccine-data-ahead-moment-lyme-light&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Pfizer, Valneva boosted by updated vaccine data ahead of moment in the Lyme-light&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/pfizer-valneva-boosted-updated-vaccine-data-ahead-moment-lyme-light</link><description><![CDATA[Valneva has reported phase 2 data on the third booster dose of its Pfizer-partnered Lyme disease vaccine candidate, ticking off another task for a prospect that could reach regulatory review next year.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/treeline-biosciences-reaps-200m-series-extension-picks-first-three-clinical-fruit&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Treeline reaps $200M series A extension, plucks first 3 clinical candidates&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/treeline-biosciences-reaps-200m-series-extension-picks-first-three-clinical-fruit</link><description><![CDATA[Treeline Biosciences has surfaced from secrecy to reveal the harvesting of a $200 million series A extension and the picking of some ripe clinical programs. The extra cash brings the Massachusetts-based oncology outfit’s total funding to $1.1 billion.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/fda-proposal-would-allow-single-arm-trials-confirmatory-evidence-ultra-rare-diseases&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;UPDATE: Analyst questions impact of FDA&apos;s rare disease pathway proposal &lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/fda-proposal-would-allow-single-arm-trials-confirmatory-evidence-ultra-rare-diseases</link><description><![CDATA[The FDA has outlined a new review process for drugs and biologics designed to treat ultra-rare genetic diseases that would allow a single-arm trial, plus other supportive data, to serve as pivotal evidence.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/wave-rna-editing-restores-enzyme-alpha-1antitrypsin-deficiency-trial-investors-unimpressed&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Wave RNA editing restores enzyme in genetic condition but underwhelms investors&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/wave-rna-editing-restores-enzyme-alpha-1antitrypsin-deficiency-trial-investors-unimpressed</link><description><![CDATA[After becoming the first group to therapeutically edit human RNA in October 2024, Wave Life Sciences has released more data from an ongoing alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency clinical trial—and investors appear less enthused this time around.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/gileads-kite-pharma-erodes-23b-shelf-cell-therapy-deal-shoreline-biosciences&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Gilead&apos;s Kite erodes $2.3B off-the-shelf cell therapy deal with Shoreline&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/gileads-kite-pharma-erodes-23b-shelf-cell-therapy-deal-shoreline-biosciences</link><description><![CDATA[Gilead Sciences' Kite Pharma has cut off a collaboration with Shoreline Biosciences, ending a research collaboration on off-the-shelf cell therapies that was valued at more than $2.3 billion.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/amgens-stomach-cancer-candidate-takes-turn-attenuated-os-benefits-final-phase-3-analysis&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Amgen-Zai stomach cancer candidate takes a turn with &apos;attenuated&apos; OS benefits at final phase 3 analysis &lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/amgens-stomach-cancer-candidate-takes-turn-attenuated-os-benefits-final-phase-3-analysis</link><description><![CDATA[An interim analysis reported in June showed that Amgen's Zai Labs-partnered bemarituzumab made improvements in overall survival, but the final analysis tells a different story.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/rash-selling-sanofi-shares-slump-phase-3-eczema-win-fails-soothe-market-fears&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Sanofi phase 3 eczema win falls short of analyst expectations &lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/rash-selling-sanofi-shares-slump-phase-3-eczema-win-fails-soothe-market-fears</link><description><![CDATA[A phase 3 trial of Sanofi’s eczema prospect amlitelimab has hit its primary and key secondary endpoints. Yet, with the data falling short of analyst expectations, shares in the company opened down 9% in Paris.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/enveda-harvests-another-150m-advance-nature-inspired-drugs&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Enveda harvests another $150M to advance nature-inspired drugs&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/enveda-harvests-another-150m-advance-nature-inspired-drugs</link><description><![CDATA[Enveda has closed its second $150 million financing round of the year. The series D round, which moves Enveda’s total funding beyond $500 million, positions the biotech to advance a crop of programs into the clinic behind its phase 1b eczema prospect.<br>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/vc-atlas-lands-400m-existing-biotech-portfolio&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;VC Atlas lands $400M to support existing biotech portfolio&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/vc-atlas-lands-400m-existing-biotech-portfolio</link><description><![CDATA[Nine months after closing a $450 million fundraise, Atlas Venture is back with another biotech financing vehicle, raising $400 million this time.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/ac-immune-cuts-workforce-30-trims-pipeline-preserve-cash&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;AC Immune cuts workforce by 30%, trims pipeline to preserve cash&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/ac-immune-cuts-workforce-30-trims-pipeline-preserve-cash</link><description><![CDATA[AC Immune is reducing its workforce by around 30% and narrowing its pipeline to extend its cash runway by about six months.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/fierce-biotech-layoff-tracker-2025&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Fierce Biotech Layoff Tracker 2025: AC Immune cuts 30% of staff; Novartis plans 58 layoffs&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/fierce-biotech-layoff-tracker-2025</link><description><![CDATA[As always, if you know of layoffs occurring at a biotech, please reach out to the Fierce Biotech editorial team.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/fda-announces-plan-publish-drug-rejection-letters-real-time-releases-new-batch-including&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;FDA moves to publish drug rejection letters in real time, releases new batch including Replimune&apos;s high-profile snub&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/fda-announces-plan-publish-drug-rejection-letters-real-time-releases-new-batch-including</link><description><![CDATA[The Food and Drug Administration today announced a plan to publicly release complete response letters at the same time they are issued to sponsoring companies, part of what the agency calls a push toward “radical transparency.”]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/fierce-biotech-fundraising-tracker-25&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Fierce Biotech Fundraising Tracker &apos;25: MRM Health nets $64M; Treeline gathers $200M&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/fierce-biotech-fundraising-tracker-25</link><description><![CDATA[The Fierce Biotech Fundraising Tracker records venture capital rounds of $50 million or more secured by biotechs.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/biontechs-her2-adc-beats-roches-kadcyla-phase-3-breast-cancer-trial&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;BioNTech&apos;s HER2 ADC beats Roche&apos;s Kadcyla in phase 3 breast cancer trial&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/biontechs-her2-adc-beats-roches-kadcyla-phase-3-breast-cancer-trial</link><description><![CDATA[BioNTech’s HER2 antibody-drug conjugate has beaten Roche’s Kadcyla in a phase 3 breast cancer trial, positioning the company’s partner Duality Biologics to seek approval for the candidate in China.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/chutes-ladders-merck-kgaa-lands-new-rd-chief&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Chutes &amp; Ladders—Merck KGaA lands new R&amp;D chief&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/chutes-ladders-merck-kgaa-lands-new-rd-chief</link><description><![CDATA[The German pharma giant has found a new pipeline leader in David Weinreich, M.D., who is joining the company as global head of R&amp;D and chief medical officer for its healthcare unit. Weinreich, who will work out of Merck’s Massachusetts R&amp;D site, was most recently an operating partner and senior advisor at Foresite Labs and Foresite Capital Management.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/led-ex-hi-bio-ceo-braveheart-pays-65m-challenge-bms-heart-disease-market-0&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Led by ex-HI-Bio CEO, Braveheart pays $65M to challenge BMS for heart disease market&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/led-ex-hi-bio-ceo-braveheart-pays-65m-challenge-bms-heart-disease-market-0</link><description><![CDATA[Braveheart Bio has waded into the fight for a heart disease market, paying $65 million upfront for a rival to Bristol Myers Squibb’s Camzyos and Cytokinetics’ aficamten.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>&lt;a href=&quot;/biotech/several-concerning-observations-fda-sheds-more-light-rejected-drugs&quot; hreflang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&apos;Several concerning observations&apos;: FDA sheds more light on reasons it rejected drugs&lt;/a&gt;</title><link>https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/several-concerning-observations-fda-sheds-more-light-rejected-drugs</link><description><![CDATA[The FDA’s ongoing effort to establish a culture of “radical transparency” saw the agency publish another haul of complete response letters yesterday.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BioMarin Announces Positive Pivotal Phase 3 Data for PALYNZIQ® (pegvaliase-pqpz) in Adolescents with Phenylketonuria at 15th International Congress of Inborn Errors of Metabolism</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/biomarin-announces-positive-pivotal-phase-3-data-for-palynziq-pegvaliase-pqpz-in-adolescents-with-phenylketonuria-at-15th-international-congress-of-inborn-errors-of-metabolism-302547986.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>New data from Phase 3 PEGASUS study demonstrates a 49.7% decrease in mean blood Phe levels in adolescents aged 12-17 treated with PALYNZIQ BioMarin's planned submission to global health authorities on track for second half of 2025 SAN RAFAEL, Calif., Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- BioMarin...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lung Cancer Genetics Study Launches Open-Source Data Platform to Research Community</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/06/3145690/0/en/Lung-Cancer-Genetics-Study-Launches-Open-Source-Data-Platform-to-Research-Community.html</link><description><![CDATA[Secure access to one of the most diverse lung cancer genetics cohorts ever assembled is now available for FREE to qualified researchers.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lung Cancer Genetics Study Launches Open-Source Data Platform to Research Community</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/06/3145690/0/en/Lung-Cancer-Genetics-Study-Launches-Open-Source-Data-Platform-to-Research-Community.html</link><description><![CDATA[Secure access to one of the most diverse lung cancer genetics cohorts ever assembled is now available for FREE to qualified researchers.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital Health Market worth US$573.5 billion by 2030 with 23.6% CAGR | MarketsandMarkets™</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/digital-health-market-worth-us573-5-billion-by-2030-with-23-6-cagr--marketsandmarkets-302547830.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>DELRAY BEACH, Fla., Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- The global Digital Health Market, valued at US$162.1 billion in 2024, stood at US$199.1 billion in 2025 and is projected to advance at a resilient CAGR of 23.6% from 2025 to 2030, culminating in a forecasted valuation of US$573.5 billion...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibody Discovery Market worth US$3.54 billion by 2030 with 13.3% CAGR | MarketsandMarkets™</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/antibody-discovery-market-worth-us3-54-billion-by-2030-with-13-3-cagr--marketsandmarkets-302547784.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>DELRAY BEACH, Fla., Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ --The global Antibody Discovery Services Market, valued at US$1.68 billion in 2024, stood at US$1.90 billion in 2025 and is projected to advance at a resilient CAGR of 13.3% from 2025 to 2030, culminating in a forecasted valuation of US$3.54...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sensor Patch Market worth $23.91 billion by 2030 - Exclusive Report by MarketsandMarkets™</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/sensor-patch-market-worth-23-91-billion-by-2030---exclusive-report-by-marketsandmarkets-302547579.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>DELRAY BEACH, Fla., Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- The global sensor patch market is projected to grow from USD 6.32 billion in 2025 to USD 23.91 billion by 2030, at a CAGR of 30.5% according to a new report by MarketsandMarkets™. A wearable sensor patch uses various sensing and...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CERN’s FPGA Failure and the Suppression of 3D-Flow and 3D-CBS: A Call to Save Millions of Lives and Billions of Euros</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/06/3145609/0/en/CERN-s-FPGA-Failure-and-the-Suppression-of-3D-Flow-and-3D-CBS-A-Call-to-Save-Millions-of-Lives-and-Billions-of-Euros.html</link><description><![CDATA[Despite reaching 300 million people, no refutation from institutions: urgently fund the inventor to prove 3D-Flow & 3D-CBS can halve cancer deaths]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crunch Fitness Franchisee Fitness Ventures Announces Annual 9/11 Remembrance Stair Climb Challenge to Honor First Responders</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/crunch-fitness-franchisee-fitness-ventures-announces-annual-911-remembrance-stair-climb-challenge-to-honor-first-responders-302548089.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>ORLANDO, Fla., Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Fitness Ventures, one of the fastest-growing Crunch Fitness franchisees, will host its annual 9/11 Remembrance Stair Climb Challenge on Thursday, September 11, 2025 at all Fitness Ventures–operated Crunch locations across 28 states. The event...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion: I inserted myself into a conversation at a bar about Covid and vaccines. Here’s what happened</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/06/covid-misinformation-bar-strangers-public-health-science/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[What happened when a public health scientist overheard four men sharing misinformation about Covid — and decided to talk to them about it.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion: STAT readers weigh in on fake CPR, a Nobel Peace Prize for Trump and Operation Warp Speed, and more</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/06/operation-warp-speed-nobel-peace-prize-trump/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[STAT readers weigh in on whether Donald Trump should win a Nobel Peace Prize for Operation Warp Speed.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lygos Clinic lance des forfaits VIP tout compris pour le tourisme dentaire à destination des patients internationaux</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/06/3145594/0/fr/Lygos-Clinic-lance-des-forfaits-VIP-tout-compris-pour-le-tourisme-dentaire-%C3%A0-destination-des-patients-internationaux.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>ISTANBUL,  06 sept. 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Lygos Clinic, centre dentaire de premier plan à Istanbul, a officiellement lancé ses nouveaux <strong>forfaits VIP tout compris de tourisme dentaire</strong>, conçus pour répondre à la demande mondiale croissante en dentisterie esthétique haut de gamme et abordable. Cette initiative stratégique améliore non seulement l’expérience des patients internationaux, mais renforce également la position de la Turquie comme destination de classe mondiale pour les <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=JLAGYSeHCpfhbxmRnFGewNqrN5sgE0T8J6tzkoFJfZlePn68nd4jKRaqwYolOU--lMJuK1-XVvk4JSaRxX24nO81nfEd4LsZ2AYJbpThyWo=" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="soins dentaires">soins dentaires</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lygos Clinic führt VIP-All-inclusive-Pakete für internationalen Zahntourismus ein</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/06/3145594/0/de/Lygos-Clinic-f%C3%BChrt-VIP-All-inclusive-Pakete-f%C3%BCr-internationalen-Zahntourismus-ein.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>ISTANBUL, Sept.  06, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Die Lygos Clinic, ein führendes zahnmedizinisches Zentrum in Istanbul, hat offiziell ihre neuen <strong>VIP-All-inclusive-Pakete für Zahntourismus</strong> eingeführt, die auf die weltweit steigende Nachfrage nach hochwertiger und zugleich erschwinglicher ästhetischer Zahnmedizin zugeschnitten sind. Dieser strategische Schritt verbessert nicht nur das Erlebnis für internationale Patientinnen und Patienten, sondern stärkt auch die Position der <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=pHtkupUfcYBd1rGhfq15fjpUZIuBNMV8CSVtzzVhTGbV6_sa6IfBZPT4f5qxX5Y1V5oxsSpAh3eagnEfERZPH_GJQQYeRXGDXOYk1vgwTlTRTWs0wpi_Lc7WR6EFhij76B9nPKnZ1ICriDPxwqxiJwJ_7EvFCXqIkCPZXRA1b4k=" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Türkei als weltweit führendes Reiseziel für Zahnbehandlungen">Türkei als weltweit führendes Reiseziel für Zahnbehandlungen</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RYBREVANT®▼ (amivantamab) plus LAZCLUZE®▼ (lazertinib) reduces acquired resistance versus osimertinib in first-line EGFR-mutated advanced non-small cell lung cancer</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/06/3145593/0/en/RYBREVANT-amivantamab-plus-LAZCLUZE-lazertinib-reduces-acquired-resistance-versus-osimertinib-in-first-line-EGFR-mutated-advanced-non-small-cell-lung-cancer.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p><em>New data demonstrate amivantamab combination significantly reduces common EGFR and MET resistance mutations seen with EGFR TKIs</em><em><sup>1</sup></em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 07:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RYBREVANT® (amivantamab-vmjw) plus LAZCLUZE® (lazertinib) prevents acquired resistance versus osimertinib in first-line EGFR-mutated non-small cell lung cancer</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/rybrevant-amivantamab-vmjw-plus-lazcluze-lazertinib-prevents-acquired-resistance-versus-osimertinib-in-first-line-egfr-mutated-non-small-cell-lung-cancer-302548296.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>RYBREVANT® combination extends survival and significantly reduces common EGFR and MET resistance mutations seen with osimertinib-based treatment BARCELONA, Spain, Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Johnson & Johnson (NYSE:JNJ) today announced new analyses from the Phase 3 MARIPOSA study...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manulife and UpLink Announce Winners of the &apos;Innovating for Asia&apos;s Demographic Future Challenge&apos;</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/manulife-and-uplink-announce-winners-of-the-innovating-for-asias-demographic-future-challenge-302548051.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Challenge is second of three in a multiyear partnership to help shape the future of longevity innovation C$ unless otherwise stated TSX/NYSE/PSE: MFC SEHK: 945 HONG KONG, Sept. 6, 2025 /PRNewswire/ - Manulife, in collaboration with UpLink, the World Economic Forum's early-stage innovation...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: RFK Jr.’s sister, nephew call for him to resign from HHS</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/rfk-jr-resign-call-kerry-kennedy/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[“Enough is enough”: RFK Jr.’s sister and other Kennedy family members are calling for the HHS secretary to step down.]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 6 Sep 2025 01:12:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revive Therapeutics Announces Extension of Proposed Private Placement</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145577/0/en/Revive-Therapeutics-Announces-Extension-of-Proposed-Private-Placement.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">TORONTO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Revive Therapeutics Ltd. (“Revive” or the “Company”) (OTCQB: RVVTF) (CSE: RVV) (FRANKFURT: 31R), a specialty life sciences company dedicated to developing innovative therapeutics for critical medical needs, announces that it is extending is previously announced private placement offering of up to 30,952,381 units, at a price of $0.021 per unit, for gross proceeds to Revive of up to $650,000. Revive closed a first tranche of the private placement in early August 2025 (see press release of August 11, 2025) by issuing 2,900,000 units of the Company, at a price of $0.021 per unit, for total gross proceeds to Revive of $60,900. Accordingly, the Company may close an additional $589,000 worth of units pursuant to the private placement.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revive Therapeutics Announces Extension of Proposed Private Placement</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145577/0/en/Revive-Therapeutics-Announces-Extension-of-Proposed-Private-Placement.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">TORONTO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Revive Therapeutics Ltd. (“Revive” or the “Company”) (OTCQB: RVVTF) (CSE: RVV) (FRANKFURT: 31R), a specialty life sciences company dedicated to developing innovative therapeutics for critical medical needs, announces that it is extending is previously announced private placement offering of up to 30,952,381 units, at a price of $0.021 per unit, for gross proceeds to Revive of up to $650,000. Revive closed a first tranche of the private placement in early August 2025 (see press release of August 11, 2025) by issuing 2,900,000 units of the Company, at a price of $0.021 per unit, for total gross proceeds to Revive of $60,900. Accordingly, the Company may close an additional $589,000 worth of units pursuant to the private placement.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: FDA will convene Digital Health Advisory Committee in November</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/fda-digital-health-advisory-committee-november-meeting/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[The FDA will convene a meeting of external digital health advisors on Nov. 6, according to an email reviewed by STAT.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 22:17:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIOVAXYS ANNOUNCES SHARE CONSOLIDATION</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/biovaxys-announces-share-consolidation-302548037.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>VANCOUVER, BC, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- BioVaxys Technology Corp. (CSE: BIOV) (FRA: 5LB) (OTCQB: BVAXF) ("BioVaxys" or the "Company") announces, further to its news release dated August 27, 2025, the consolidation of its common shares ("Common Shares") on the basis of ten (10)...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Bipartisan bill to extend ACA tax credits offers hope for a deal</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/aca-tax-credit-extension-bipartisan-bill-introduced/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[A group of Republicans and Democrats is proposing a one-year extension of tax credits that help people afford health insurance under the ACA.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:47:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Helios Alliance Announces National Opioid Conference Featuring Former White House Drug Policy Director Dr. Rahul Gupta</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145507/0/en/Helios-Alliance-Announces-National-Opioid-Conference-Featuring-Former-White-House-Drug-Policy-Director-Dr-Rahul-Gupta.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Mobile, Alabama , Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- <a href="https://www.theheliosalliance.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=""><em>Helios Alliance</em></a>, a nonprofit dedicated to improving public health outcomes, announced today that <strong>Dr. Rahul Gupta</strong>, former director of the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy, will headline the <strong>Reimagining Opioid Abatement Conference</strong> in Mobile on October 22, 2025. The event will bring together public health leaders, policymakers, and frontline workers to explore community-based solutions for the opioid crisis.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lipocine to Present at H.C. Wainwright 27th Annual Global Investment Conference</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/lipocine-to-present-at-hc-wainwright-27th-annual-global-investment-conference-302547924.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>SALT LAKE CITY, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Lipocine Inc. (NASDAQ: LPCN), a biopharmaceutical company leveraging its proprietary technology platform to develop innovative products with effective oral delivery, today announced that Company Management will present and meet with investors...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Publication relating to transparency notifications</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145495/0/en/Publication-relating-to-transparency-notifications.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>                </p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Publication relative à des notifications de transparence</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145495/0/fr/Publication-relative-%C3%A0-des-notifications-de-transparence.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>        </p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBV Technologies Establishes an At-The-Market (ATM) Program on Nasdaq</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145496/0/en/DBV-Technologies-Establishes-an-At-The-Market-ATM-Program-on-Nasdaq.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="right">Châtillon, France, September 5, 2025</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBV Technologies met en place un Programme At-The-Market (ATM) sur le Nasdaq</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145496/0/fr/DBV-Technologies-met-en-place-un-Programme-At-The-Market-ATM-sur-le-Nasdaq.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="right">Châtillon, France, le 5 septembre (22:30 CEST) 2025 </p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBV Technologies Establishes an At-The-Market (ATM) Program on Nasdaq</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145496/0/en/DBV-Technologies-Establishes-an-At-The-Market-ATM-Program-on-Nasdaq.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="right">Châtillon, France, September 5, 2025</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBV Technologies met en place un Programme At-The-Market (ATM) sur le Nasdaq</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145496/0/fr/DBV-Technologies-met-en-place-un-Programme-At-The-Market-ATM-sur-le-Nasdaq.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="right">Châtillon, France, le 5 septembre (22:30 CEST) 2025 </p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American Healthcare REIT to Participate at BofA Securities 2025 Global Real Estate Conference</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/american-healthcare-reit-to-participate-at-bofa-securities-2025-global-real-estate-conference-302546976.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>IRVINE, Calif., Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- American Healthcare REIT, Inc. (NYSE: AHR) ("Company") announced today that Danny Prosky, the Company's President and Chief Executive Officer, Brian Peay, the Company's Chief Financial Officer, and Alan Peterson, the Company's Vice President...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PROCURE PROTON THERAPY CENTER URGES NEWS ORGANIZATIONS TO RAISE AWARENESS OF PROTON THERAPY FOR PROSTATE CANCER</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/procure-proton-therapy-center-urges-news-organizations-to-raise-awareness-of-proton-therapy-for-prostate-cancer-302548055.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>SOMERSET, N.J., Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- With prostate cancer affecting one in eight men, ProCure Proton Therapy Center is calling on news media to help educate the public about the benefits of proton therapy, a powerful and precise treatment often misunderstood by patients and...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Artivion to Participate in Morgan Stanley 23rd Annual Global Healthcare Conference</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/artivion-to-participate-in-morgan-stanley-23rd-annual-global-healthcare-conference-302547997.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>ATLANTA, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Artivion, Inc. (NYSE: AORT), a leading cardiac and vascular surgery company focused on aortic disease, today announced that it will participate at the upcoming Morgan Stanley 23rd Annual Global Healthcare Conference on Wednesday, September 10, 2025,...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vera Therapeutics Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145481/0/en/Vera-Therapeutics-Announces-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>BRISBANE, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Vera Therapeutics, Inc. (Nasdaq: VERA) today announced that, on September 4, 2025, the Compensation Committee of Vera’s Board of Directors granted inducement awards consisting of non-qualified stock options to purchase 85,000 shares of Class A common stock and restricted stock units (RSUs) underlying 45,250 shares of Class A common stock to eight (8) new employees under the Vera Therapeutics, Inc. 2024 Inducement Plan (Inducement Plan). The Compensation Committee approved the awards as an inducement material to the new employees’ employment in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Artelo Biosciences Announces Closing of $3.0 Million Public Offering</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145482/0/en/Artelo-Biosciences-Announces-Closing-of-3-0-Million-Public-Offering.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">SOLANA BEACH, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=O9frFnWfsf1kJb3EJownFiQwt5nXMBMi4bM7ZstRGxvVO6-OoTn1NJT1m9UdMMs4jGLBCQxDgsqAQSpSpoKfwdPVBMhRlmAbodsUTQ0FOn7YaIjiTZcGXKhJ7vU6obgsE17MP0MFyZK6aL4pnajLKZPPadu-DkeOYSRvB2-R_c0iXZuLj14jAKfz8jLa-Pv4XZ_1_sjm6ygM2EeTgSnPibzoZVLrCAW_EZ6WuJpG_cO6_szMy4fHQpptnS18a-Rlo4OCDp5EjghokpuweqC-KQ==" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Artelo Biosciences, Inc.">Artelo Biosciences, Inc.</a><strong> (Nasdaq: ARTL)</strong><strong>,</strong> a clinical-stage pharmaceutical company focused on modulating lipid-signaling pathways to develop treatments for people living with cancer, pain, dermatologic, or neurological conditions, today announced the closing of its previously announced underwritten public offering of 640,924 shares of its common stock at a price to the public of $4.40 per share and pre-funded warrants to purchase up to 40,894 shares of Artelo’s common stock at a price to the public of $4.399 per pre-funded warrant, which represents the per share public offering price of each share of Artelo’s common stock less the $0.001 per share exercise price for each pre-funded warrant.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>89bio Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145485/0/en/89bio-Announces-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">SAN FRANCISCO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- 89bio, Inc. (the “Company” or “89bio”) (Nasdaq: ETNB), a clinical-stage biopharmaceutical company focused on the development and commercialization of innovative therapies for the treatment of liver and cardiometabolic diseases, today announced that the Compensation Committee of the Company’s Board of Directors approved the grant of non-qualified stock options to purchase an aggregate of 64,750 shares of the Company’s common stock to three new employees (the “Inducement Grants”) on September 1, 2025 (the “Grant Date”). The Inducement Grants have been granted pursuant to the Company’s 2023 Inducement Plan (the “Plan”). The Inducement Grants were granted as an inducement material to these individuals entering into employment with 89bio in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ORIC Pharmaceuticals Reports Inducement Grants under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145486/0/en/ORIC-Pharmaceuticals-Reports-Inducement-Grants-under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">SOUTH SAN FRANCISCO, Calif. and SAN DIEGO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- ORIC Pharmaceuticals, Inc. (Nasdaq:ORIC), a clinical stage oncology company focused on developing treatments that address mechanisms of therapeutic resistance, today announced that on September 2, 2025 (the “Grant Date”), ORIC granted a total of 292,500 non-qualified stock options and 79,000 restricted stock units to one new non-executive officer employee who began their employment with ORIC in August 2025.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rapport Therapeutics to Announce Topline Results for RAP-219 Phase 2a Trial in Focal Onset Seizures on Monday, September 8, 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145488/0/en/Rapport-Therapeutics-to-Announce-Topline-Results-for-RAP-219-Phase-2a-Trial-in-Focal-Onset-Seizures-on-Monday-September-8-2025.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">BOSTON and SAN DIEGO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Rapport Therapeutics, Inc. (Nasdaq: RAPP) (“Rapport” or the “Company”), a clinical-stage biotechnology company dedicated to the discovery and development of small molecule precision medicines for patients with neurological or psychiatric disorders, today announced that it will host a conference call and live webcast at 8:00 am ET on September 8, 2025, to report topline results for the Phase 2a trial of RAP-219 in patients with drug-resistant focal onset seizures.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gyre Therapeutics to Present at the H.C. Wainwright 27th Annual Global Investment Conference</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145489/0/en/Gyre-Therapeutics-to-Present-at-the-H-C-Wainwright-27th-Annual-Global-Investment-Conference.html</link><description><![CDATA[Gyre Therapeutics to Present at the H.C. Wainwright 27th Annual Global Investment Conference]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Artelo Biosciences Announces Closing of $3.0 Million Public Offering</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145482/0/en/Artelo-Biosciences-Announces-Closing-of-3-0-Million-Public-Offering.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">SOLANA BEACH, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=O9frFnWfsf1kJb3EJownFiQwt5nXMBMi4bM7ZstRGxvVO6-OoTn1NJT1m9UdMMs4jGLBCQxDgsqAQSpSpoKfwdPVBMhRlmAbodsUTQ0FOn7YaIjiTZcGXKhJ7vU6obgsE17MP0MFyZK6aL4pnajLKZPPadu-DkeOYSRvB2-R_c0iXZuLj14jAKfz8jLa-Pv4XZ_1_sjm6ygM2EeTgSnPibzoZVLrCAW_EZ6WuJpG_cO6_szMy4fHQpptnS18a-Rlo4OCDp5EjghokpuweqC-KQ==" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="Artelo Biosciences, Inc.">Artelo Biosciences, Inc.</a><strong> (Nasdaq: ARTL)</strong><strong>,</strong> a clinical-stage pharmaceutical company focused on modulating lipid-signaling pathways to develop treatments for people living with cancer, pain, dermatologic, or neurological conditions, today announced the closing of its previously announced underwritten public offering of 640,924 shares of its common stock at a price to the public of $4.40 per share and pre-funded warrants to purchase up to 40,894 shares of Artelo’s common stock at a price to the public of $4.399 per pre-funded warrant, which represents the per share public offering price of each share of Artelo’s common stock less the $0.001 per share exercise price for each pre-funded warrant.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>89bio Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145485/0/en/89bio-Announces-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">SAN FRANCISCO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- 89bio, Inc. (the “Company” or “89bio”) (Nasdaq: ETNB), a clinical-stage biopharmaceutical company focused on the development and commercialization of innovative therapies for the treatment of liver and cardiometabolic diseases, today announced that the Compensation Committee of the Company’s Board of Directors approved the grant of non-qualified stock options to purchase an aggregate of 64,750 shares of the Company’s common stock to three new employees (the “Inducement Grants”) on September 1, 2025 (the “Grant Date”). The Inducement Grants have been granted pursuant to the Company’s 2023 Inducement Plan (the “Plan”). The Inducement Grants were granted as an inducement material to these individuals entering into employment with 89bio in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ORIC Pharmaceuticals Reports Inducement Grants under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145486/0/en/ORIC-Pharmaceuticals-Reports-Inducement-Grants-under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">SOUTH SAN FRANCISCO, Calif. and SAN DIEGO, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- ORIC Pharmaceuticals, Inc. (Nasdaq:ORIC), a clinical stage oncology company focused on developing treatments that address mechanisms of therapeutic resistance, today announced that on September 2, 2025 (the “Grant Date”), ORIC granted a total of 292,500 non-qualified stock options and 79,000 restricted stock units to one new non-executive officer employee who began their employment with ORIC in August 2025.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gyre Therapeutics to Present at the H.C. Wainwright 27th Annual Global Investment Conference</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145489/0/en/Gyre-Therapeutics-to-Present-at-the-H-C-Wainwright-27th-Annual-Global-Investment-Conference.html</link><description><![CDATA[Gyre Therapeutics to Present at the H.C. Wainwright 27th Annual Global Investment Conference]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tampa General Hospital Receives FACT Accreditation in Continued Commitment to World-Class, Innovative Cancer Care</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tampa-general-hospital-receives-fact-accreditation-in-continued-commitment-to-world-class-innovative-cancer-care-302548043.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>FACT Accreditation represents a gold seal of quality and safety in the world of stem cell transplant and cellular therapy. TAMPA, Fla., Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- As they continue to bring leading-edge cancer care to the region, Tampa General Hospital (TGH) and the TGH Cancer Institute...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adverum Biotechnologies Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145476/32452/en/Adverum-Biotechnologies-Announces-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>REDWOOD CITY, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Adverum Biotechnologies, Inc. (Nasdaq: ADVM) today announced that the Compensation Committee of Adverum’s Board of Directors granted inducement awards consisting of non-qualified stock options to purchase 16,860 shares of common stock and restricted stock units (RSUs) for 8,430 shares of common stock to two new employees under Adverum’s 2017 Inducement Plan. These awards were approved as an inducement material to the new employees entering into employment with Adverum in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syndax Pharmaceuticals Reports Inducement Grants Under NASDAQ Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145477/0/en/Syndax-Pharmaceuticals-Reports-Inducement-Grants-Under-NASDAQ-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">NEW YORK, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Syndax Pharmaceuticals (Nasdaq: <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=JKpyIwhuVaCVLDkPCuLZXra0SCwc-myTtUtM_nRO7AcrB6uVLxuZ-3oC4oJaSF4K2smXHI91UWolaPcZsg0nxrB0hWptk_ENZeKl_J12ds59etNOlUf1ozfgssmM_TRM7GdtxRmIDWuOaP6eTkYQrq1veNhCF7n_89_TyZN6KRT5sruPVBwWw-tEisbVM5CI3xsaIA6Way-Qx_NT0w0n-R_24PeAZxRPX2YZsnltHCx9T2MAgMcZhEjuXhpjv8kC" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="SNDX">SNDX</a>), a commercial-stage biopharmaceutical company advancing innovative cancer therapies, today announced that on September 1, 2025 the Company granted inducement awards to purchase up to 167,400 shares of common stock to 11 new employees under the Company's 2023 Inducement Plan. The stock options will vest over four years, with 25% of the underlying shares vesting on the one-year anniversary of the vesting commencement date and 1/48th of the underlying shares vesting monthly thereafter over 36 months, subject to the employee's continued service relationship with Syndax through the applicable vesting dates.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adverum Biotechnologies Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145476/32452/en/Adverum-Biotechnologies-Announces-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>REDWOOD CITY, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Adverum Biotechnologies, Inc. (Nasdaq: ADVM) today announced that the Compensation Committee of Adverum’s Board of Directors granted inducement awards consisting of non-qualified stock options to purchase 16,860 shares of common stock and restricted stock units (RSUs) for 8,430 shares of common stock to two new employees under Adverum’s 2017 Inducement Plan. These awards were approved as an inducement material to the new employees entering into employment with Adverum in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>aTyr Pharma Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145473/0/en/aTyr-Pharma-Announces-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[aTyr Pharma Announces Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arcutis Biotherapeutics Reports Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145475/0/en/Arcutis-Biotherapeutics-Reports-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">WESTLAKE VILLAGE, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=1mpPCVR9f9uJMhSDVANNSdJepACbNmew2BVE9PIHdy54bE2A0fJGMX1Qya1pkMlKzoYtgtDLamBOH9Ufz3tRO6cs-ulZ85oewZsx6T8qEEM=" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title=""><u>Arcutis Biotherapeutics, Inc.</u></a> (Nasdaq: ARQT), a commercial-stage biopharmaceutical company focused on developing meaningful innovations in immuno-dermatology, today reported the grant of an aggregate of 35,500 restricted stock units of Arcutis’ common stock to four newly hired employees. These awards were approved by the Compensation Committee of Arcutis’ Board of Directors and granted under the Arcutis Biotherapeutics, Inc. 2022 Inducement Plan, with a grant date of September 2, 2025, as an inducement material to the new employees entering into employment with Arcutis, in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PERRIGO TEAMSTERS IN NEW YORK LAUNCH STRIKE</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/perrigo-teamsters-in-new-york-launch-strike-302548031.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Local 210 Calls Out Pharmaceutical Manufacturer for Trying to Slash Workers' Benefits BRONX, N.Y., Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Members of Teamsters Local 210 are on strike at Perrigo Company's Bronx manufacturing facilities after the employer attempted to eliminate workers' overtime...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PAR Celebrates Annual United Way Week with Record-Breaking Community Impact</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/par-celebrates-annual-united-way-week-with-record-breaking-community-impact-302548029.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>TAMPA, Fla., Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- PAR (Psychological Assessment Resources, Inc.) proudly wrapped up its annual United Way Week, celebrating a legacy of giving, volunteerism, and community partnership. With events centered around community engagement, prioritizing employee...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISX Financial EU plc obtiene una patente de tecnología innovadora para la verificación de identidad</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/isx-financial-eu-plc-obtiene-una-patente-de-tecnologia-innovadora-para-la-verificacion-de-identidad-302548010.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>ISX Financial EU plc obtiene una patente de tecnología innovadora para la verificación de identidad mediante KYC con vídeo ininterrumpido NICOSIA, Chipre, 5 de septiembre de 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- ISX Financial EU plc se complace en anunciar que su filial de propiedad exclusiva, ISX IP Ltd,...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 19:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Host Proteins Identified in SARS-CoV-2 Replication Pathways Reveal Drug Targets</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/infectious-diseases/host-proteins-identified-in-sars-cov-2-replication-pathways-reveal-drug-targets/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>The identification of human proteins essential to SARS-CoV-2 replication reveal new drug targets. Targeting these host factors could lead to broad coronavirus treatments resistant to viral mutation and future outbreaks.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/infectious-diseases/host-proteins-identified-in-sars-cov-2-replication-pathways-reveal-drug-targets/">Host Proteins Identified in SARS-CoV-2 Replication Pathways Reveal Drug Targets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 19:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CDC’s vaccine information no longer entirely trustworthy, former director says</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/former-cdc-director-advises-against-current-cdc-guidance/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[The former CDC director says vaccine information on CDC website is no longer entirely trustworthy and urges people to get vaccine guidance elsewhere.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 19:04:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Run. Rally. Rise. The 2025 Race to End Women&apos;s Cancer is Back in Washington, D.C.</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/run-rally-rise-the-2025-race-to-end-womens-cancer-is-back-in-washington-dc-302547992.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>WASHINGTON, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Every five minutes, someone in the United States is diagnosed with a gynecologic cancer, contributing to nearly 115,000 new cases annually. September is Gynecologic Cancer Awareness Month and the Foundation for Women's Cancer (FWC) invites you to...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Patient groups cheer as the WHO adds diabetes and cystic fibrosis drugs to its essential medicines list</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/pharmalot/2025/09/05/who-medicines-pharma-biotech-diabetes-obesity-cystic-fibrosis-vertex-lilly-novo-sanofi/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[For the first time, the WHO has added various high-cost treatments for diabetes and cystic fibrosis to its list of essential medicines.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 18:48:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PPMD Kicks Off World Duchenne Awareness Day with Bad Shirt Friday, Special United Nations Documentary Premiere</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ppmd-kicks-off-world-duchenne-awareness-day-with-bad-shirt-friday-special-united-nations-documentary-premiere-302547962.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>WASHINGTON, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- Parent Project Muscular Dystrophy (PPMD), the largest U.S. non-profit leading Duchenne and Becker care, research, and advocacy efforts, will join forces with fellow Duchenne-specific organizations from around the world to celebrate World Duchenne...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning to Manage Chronic Aches</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/learning-to-manage-chronic-aches-302547920.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>CBD can reduce the discomfort caused by inflammation, aid sleep, and Fusion CBD Products can help with that MIAMI, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- According to a 2021 study of U.S. adults, more than 20% of the population – 51.6 million people – suffer from the discomfort of chronic aches...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NYU Langone Health Brings on Two Acclaimed Cancer Experts to Lead Ambitious New Gastrointestinal Cancer Center</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/nyu-langone-health-brings-on-two-acclaimed-cancer-experts-to-lead-ambitious-new-gastrointestinal-cancer-center-302547942.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>NEW YORK, Sept. 5, 2025 /PRNewswire/ -- NYU Langone Health's Perlmutter Cancer Center announces the arrival of acclaimed cancer leaders Anirban Maitra, MD, and Manuel Hidalgo, MD, as co-directors of a new Gastrointestinal (GI) Cancer Center. This marks a milestone in its mission to...</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion: The Trump administration’s endless quest for vaccine data is public-health gaslighting</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/more-vaccine-data-needed-gaslighting-technique-explained-by-expert/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[RFK Jr. and the rest of the Trump administration are using seven kinds of rhetorical sleight-of-hand around vaccines and transparency.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 17:24:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spaceflight Aging of Human Stem Cells May Guide Cancer and Age-Related Disorder Modeling</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/finding-that-spaceflight-accelerates-human-stem-cell-aging-could-aid-modelling-of-cancer-and-age-related-disorders/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Scientists used automated AI-driven stem cell-tracking nanobioreactor systems in four SpaceX space missions to track stem cell changes in real time, discovering that the cells showed multiple signs of accelerated aging. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/finding-that-spaceflight-accelerates-human-stem-cell-aging-could-aid-modelling-of-cancer-and-age-related-disorders/">Spaceflight Aging of Human Stem Cells May Guide Cancer and Age-Related Disorder Modeling</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 17:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond the Bioinformatics Hype: How to Build Scalable, AI-Driven Tools That Deliver in Precision Medicine</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/resources/ebooks/beyond-the-bioinformatics-hype-how-to-build-scalable-ai-driven-tools-that-deliver-in-precision-medicine/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>In this eBook, we explore key areas where bioinformatics is transforming drug discovery, diagnostics, and clinical decision-making.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/resources/ebooks/beyond-the-bioinformatics-hype-how-to-build-scalable-ai-driven-tools-that-deliver-in-precision-medicine/">Beyond the Bioinformatics Hype: How to Build Scalable, AI-Driven Tools That Deliver in Precision Medicine</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 16:53:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA gives nod to Respiree wearable for home care</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723580-fda-gives-nod-to-respiree-wearable-for-home-care</link><description><![CDATA[The U.S. FDA cleared Respiree Pte. Ltd.’s 510(k) for its RS-001 cardio-respiratory wearable that measures respiration and offers passive cardio-respiratory monitoring.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: FDA commissioner says agency is looking into question of pediatric deaths from Covid vaccines</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/fda-investigating-childhood-deaths-from-covid-vaccine/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[Commissioner Marty Makary said the FDA will release a report within weeks on childhood deaths that he said are linked to Covid shots.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 15:36:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gilead Sciences Breaks Ground on New Biomanufacturing Hub</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/bioprocessing/gilead-sciences-breaks-ground-on-new-biomanufacturing-hub/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>The five-story,180,000-sq-foot facility will serve as a hub for innovation and collaboration across technical development and manufacturing teams. It will feature digitally enabled systems, autonomous robotics, and real-time digital monitoring. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/bioprocessing/gilead-sciences-breaks-ground-on-new-biomanufacturing-hub/">Gilead Sciences Breaks Ground on New Biomanufacturing Hub</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing New Therapies Through Partnership, Electricity, and Immunotherapy</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/genome-editing/developing-new-therapies-through-partnership-electricity-and-immunotherapy/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode of <i>GEN</i>'s <i>Touching Base</i>, we discuss a new Novartis partnership, an off-the-shelf immunotherapy option, and electrically reprogramming macrophages. Eli Lilly has a successful Phase III trial for oral GLP-1.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/genome-editing/developing-new-therapies-through-partnership-electricity-and-immunotherapy/">Developing New Therapies Through Partnership, Electricity, and Immunotherapy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 14:25:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO declares end of global emergency over mpox outbreak</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/who-pheic-emergency-mpox-drc-africa/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[The African mpox outbreak no longer constitutes a public health emergency of international concern, the WHO said, even as the response must continue.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 14:18:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adagene’s ADG126 to be Highlighted in Two Presentations at the 2025 Chinese Society of Clinical Oncology (CSCO) Meeting in Jinan, China</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145312/0/en/Adagene-s-ADG126-to-be-Highlighted-in-Two-Presentations-at-the-2025-Chinese-Society-of-Clinical-Oncology-CSCO-Meeting-in-Jinan-China.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">SAN DIEGO and SUZHOU, China, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Adagene Inc. (“Adagene or the Company”) (Nasdaq: ADAG), a company transforming the discovery and development of novel antibody-based therapies, today announced that ADG126 will be highlighted in two oral presentations at this year’s CSCO Meeting, taking place September 10-14 in Jinan, China.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Up and down the ladder: The latest comings and goings</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/pharmalot/2025/09/05/jobs-biotech-pharma-ladder-sanofi-genmab-merck-icon-iqvia/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[From new hires to departures, promotions and transfers, here are the latest comings and goings in the pharmaceutical industry.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 13:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: The FDA is getting more transparent about drug rejections</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/biotech-news-fda-lsd-gilead-pfizer/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[And more biotech news stories brought to you by The Readout.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 13:32:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Pharmalittle: We’re reading about PEPFAR and a Gilead drug, the FDA’s rejection letters, and much more</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/pharmalot/2025/09/05/medicare-trump-gilead-pepfar-hiv-aids-fda-crl-cvs-wegovy-zepbound-novo-lilly-jnj-bristol-india-weight-obesity/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[The FDA said it would start releasing rejection letters soon after they are provided to drugmakers, a victory for those who wanted more transparency.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 13:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MAIA Biotechnology Abstract Selected for Poster Presentation at 2025 IASLC World Conference on Lung Cancer</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145282/0/en/MAIA-Biotechnology-Abstract-Selected-for-Poster-Presentation-at-2025-IASLC-World-Conference-on-Lung-Cancer.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="center"><strong><em>Poster details durability and efficacy of ateganosine (THIO) treatment in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)</em></strong></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralys Therapeutics Presents Subgroup Analyses of Phase 3 Launch-HTN Trial Demonstrating Efficacy and Safety of Lorundrostat in Hypertension Participants with High Unmet Medical Need</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145274/0/en/Mineralys-Therapeutics-Presents-Subgroup-Analyses-of-Phase-3-Launch-HTN-Trial-Demonstrating-Efficacy-and-Safety-of-Lorundrostat-in-Hypertension-Participants-with-High-Unmet-Medical.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="center"><em>~Pivotal Launch-HTN trial of novel aldosterone synthase inhibitor lorundrostat enrolled a diverse range of participants with uncontrolled or resistant hypertension~</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tiziana Life Sciences Announces Purchase of Shares by Chairman</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145254/0/en/Tiziana-Life-Sciences-Announces-Purchase-of-Shares-by-Chairman.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">BOSTON, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Tiziana Life Sciences, Ltd. (Nasdaq: <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=v-t4Z3VuP3euKjLQQJAw99txY3YzVMieeVVE4Vr3pSmiEJ7H1i4suDUqFzuPnkYihTTOxRUN-IaG62BAMZBlU9SlUhi3weUUizSFhfwZtzzJ7hGNJ4EZ1KxzYT5UrpQA" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="TLSA">TLSA</a>) (“Tiziana” or the “Company”), a biotechnology company developing breakthrough immunomodulation therapies with its lead development candidate, intranasal foralumab, a fully human, anti-CD3 monoclonal antibody, today announces that its Executive Chairman and Founder, Mr. Gabriele Cerrone, has purchased 25,000 common shares at $1.60 per share, bringing his total holding to 43,277,143 common shares, which is 36.28% of issued share capital.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>24/7 Market News: Kraig Labs Fibers are 5X Stronger Than Steel, Tougher than Kevlar, and Biodegradable</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145245/0/en/24-7-Market-News-Kraig-Labs-Fibers-are-5X-Stronger-Than-Steel-Tougher-than-Kevlar-and-Biodegradable.html</link><description><![CDATA[Kraig Labs (OTCQB: KBLB) is moving rapidly toward commercialization and is closing in on its first commercial sale of recombinant spider silk]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pacira BioSciences Reports Inducement Grants Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145227/0/en/Pacira-BioSciences-Reports-Inducement-Grants-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>BRISBANE, Calif., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Pacira BioSciences, Inc. (Nasdaq: PCRX), the industry leader in the delivery of innovative, non-opioid pain therapies to transform the lives of patients, today announced the granting of inducement awards on September 3, 2025 to nine new employees under Pacira’s Amended and Restated 2014 Inducement Plan (the “Inducement Plan”) as a material inducement to each employee’s entry into employment with the company. In accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4), the awards were approved by the People &amp; Compensation Committee of the Board of Directors (the “Committee”) without stockholder approval.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>electroCore Announces Departure of Peter Cuneo from the Board of Directors and Elects Thomas J. Errico, MD as Chairman of the Board</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145229/0/en/electroCore-Announces-Departure-of-Peter-Cuneo-from-the-Board-of-Directors-and-Elects-Thomas-J-Errico-MD-as-Chairman-of-the-Board.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">ROCKAWAY, N.J., Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- electroCore, Inc. (Nasdaq: ECOR), a commercial-stage bioelectronic medicine and wellness company, announced today the departure of Peter Cuneo from the Board of Directors and that Thomas J. Errico, MD, has been elected to succeed Mr. Cuneo as Chairman of the Board, effective September 2, 2025. Mr. Cuneo will continue as a strategic advisor to the Company.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taysha Gene Therapies Announces Inducement Grant Under Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4)</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145231/0/en/Taysha-Gene-Therapies-Announces-Inducement-Grant-Under-Nasdaq-Listing-Rule-5635-c-4.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="left">DALLAS, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Taysha Gene Therapies, Inc. (Nasdaq: TSHA) (Taysha or the Company), a clinical-stage biotechnology company focused on advancing adeno-associated virus (AAV)-based gene therapies for severe monogenic diseases of the central nervous system (CNS), today announced that, on September 2, 2025, the Compensation Committee of Taysha's Board of Directors granted five new employees, in the aggregate, options to purchase 225,000 shares of the Company's common stock in connection with their employment. The stock options were granted under the Taysha Gene Therapies, Inc. 2023 Inducement Plan as an inducement material to the individuals entering employment with Taysha in accordance with Nasdaq Listing Rule 5635(c)(4).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firefly Neuroscience Partners with HealingMaps to Offer Cognitive Electrophysiology Analytics to Over 2,500 Ketamine, Psilocybin, and TMS Clinics Across North America</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145225/0/en/Firefly-Neuroscience-Partners-with-HealingMaps-to-Offer-Cognitive-Electrophysiology-Analytics-to-Over-2-500-Ketamine-Psilocybin-and-TMS-Clinics-Across-North-America.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">KENMORE, N.Y. and MIAMI, Sept.  05, 2025  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Firefly Neuroscience, Inc. (“Firefly”) (NASDAQ: AIFF), an Artificial Intelligence (“AI”) company developing innovative solutions that improve brain health outcomes for patients with neurological and mental disorders, today announced a new partnership with <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=FECkz4eELvF7-OKG6pnz0yR6XCr90iWlO5clM6SN0PQA24wK_8AtivrMUESfLpJkp0af6fVfG2jcn-qNUUcHJA==" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" title="HealingMaps">HealingMaps</a>, the leading directory for ketamine, psychedelic-assisted therapy, and transcranial magnetic stimulation (“TMS”) clinics, and Advanced Behavioral Strategies (ABS).</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happened at RFK Jr.’s Senate hearing in 300 words</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/health-news-rfk-jr-hearing-vaccines-alcohol-study/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[And more health news stories from STAT's Morning Rounds.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 11:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>uniQure Announces Initial AMT-191 Phase I/IIa Data Showing Sustained Increases in α-Gal A Enzyme Activity in Patients with Fabry Disease</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/09/05/3145208/0/en/uniQure-Announces-Initial-AMT-191-Phase-I-IIa-Data-Showing-Sustained-Increases-in-%CE%B1-Gal-A-Enzyme-Activity-in-Patients-with-Fabry-Disease.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p align="center"><em>~ All patients in the first cohort achieved between 27- to 208-fold increases in α-Gal A activity relative to mean normal level ~</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion: I’m one of the Ph.D. students caught up in the cancelation of ‘diversity’ grants. I’m heartbroken</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/nih-f31-diversity-grant-applications-supreme-court-ruling-heartbreak/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[I’m one of the Ph.D. students caught up in the cancelation of ‘diversity’ grants. I’m heartbroken]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Donavon Decker knew a gene therapy experiment wouldn’t help him. To help others, he still said yes</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/gene-therapy-pioneer-donavon-decker-remembered/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[Long before there was Sarepta's gene therapy for muscular dystrophy, there was Donavon Decker and his offer to test a gene therapy.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion: The FDA’s pivot from ad comms to ‘expert’ panels is bad medicine</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/05/fda-expert-panels-advisory-committees-talc-ssris-formula/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[G. Caleb Alexander has chaired or served on more than a dozen FDA advisory committees. He’s worried the shift to ‘expert’ panels lacks transparency.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 5 Sep 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Two former top NIH officials say they were forced out in retaliation for objecting to grant terminations</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/04/nih-whistleblower-complaints-research-grants-flu-vaccine-jeanne-marrazzo/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[Whistleblower complaints by two former top NIH officials offer their inside accounts of the Trump administration’s targeting of vaccine science.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 23:16:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High-Throughput Antibody Platform May Transform Therapeutic Discovery</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/high-throughput-antibody-platform-may-transform-therapeutic-discovery/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A high-volume platform for rapidly constructing and characterizing antibodies, called oPool+ display, could potentially speed vaccine and therapeutic development.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/high-throughput-antibody-platform-may-transform-therapeutic-discovery/">High-Throughput Antibody Platform May Transform Therapeutic Discovery</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 22:44:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Structural Swaps in SCORE Protein Enable Programmable Pathogen Recognition in Plants</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/infectious-diseases/structural-swaps-in-score-protein-enable-programmable-pathogen-recognition-in-plants/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>By swapping key parts of the SCORE receptor, Riken scientists have demonstrated a mechanism for engineering plant immunity, paving the way for broad-spectrum pathogen resistance in economically important plants.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/infectious-diseases/structural-swaps-in-score-protein-enable-programmable-pathogen-recognition-in-plants/">Structural Swaps in SCORE Protein Enable Programmable Pathogen Recognition in Plants</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 22:08:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Trump administration confirms plan for PEPFAR to distribute Gilead’s new HIV prevention drug</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/pharmalot/2025/09/04/gilead-hiv-aids-pepfar-trump-lenacapavir-licensing/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA["This is a really significant moment in the fight against HIV and AIDS.”]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 20:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Possible Molecular Link Between Air Pollution and Lewy Body Dementia Identified</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/possible-molecular-link-between-air-pollution-and-lewy-body-dementia-identified/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>In mice, air pollution exposure triggered formation of an abnormal alpha-synuclein strain that shares key features with those of alpha-synuclein found in the brains of patients with Lewy body dementia.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/translational-medicine/possible-molecular-link-between-air-pollution-and-lewy-body-dementia-identified/">Possible Molecular Link Between Air Pollution and Lewy Body Dementia Identified</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>STAT+: Now, even Senate Republicans are pushing back on Kennedy’s vaccine views</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/04/kennedy-senate-testimony-analysis-mrna-vaccines-operation-warp-speed/?utm_campaign=rss</link><description><![CDATA[Three Republican senators joined Democrats in questioning Kennedy’s contradictory statements on mRNA vaccines and Operation Warp Speed.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 19:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Radiopharmaceutical Pathways: Ensuring Precision from Logistics to Manufacturing</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/multimedia/webinars/radiopharmaceutical-pathways-ensuring-precision-from-logistics-to-manufacturing/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>In this <i>GEN</i> webinar, our expert speakers—Tom Brennan (VP Nuclear Medicine at Marken-UPS Healthcare Precision Logistics) and John Zehner (CEO/President of SpectronRx)—will describe the extraordinary journey of a radiopharmaceutical dose and explore the sophisticated dance of just-in-time manufacturing, real-time GPS and temperature tracking, and the intricate coordination required between production facilities, specialized couriers, and clinical teams. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/multimedia/webinars/radiopharmaceutical-pathways-ensuring-precision-from-logistics-to-manufacturing/">Radiopharmaceutical Pathways: Ensuring Precision from Logistics to Manufacturing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 19:23:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Andelyn and Tern Therapeutics Partner on Gene Therapy Manufacturing</title><link>https://www.genengnews.com/topics/bioprocessing/andelyn-and-tern-therapeutics-partner-on-gene-therapy-manufacturing/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>TTX-381, a one-time, subretinal AAV gene therapy, is designed to deliver a functional <i>TPP1</i> gene copy directly to retinal cells to produce the missing TPP1 enzyme and preserve patient vision.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/bioprocessing/andelyn-and-tern-therapeutics-partner-on-gene-therapy-manufacturing/">Andelyn and Tern Therapeutics Partner on Gene Therapy Manufacturing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.genengnews.com">GEN - Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology News</a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 4 Sep 2025 19:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Witnesses at hearing cite trust deficit for AI in health care</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723562-witnesses-at-hearing-cite-trust-deficit-for-ai-in-health-care</link><description><![CDATA[The Sept. 3 congressional hearing on AI in health care raised questions about whether the U.S. FDA enjoys the statutory authorities it needs to properly regulate this class of products, but witnesses at the hearing said a lack of trust in AI is a substantial roadblock to adoption.]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 3 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greymind AI’s mental health platform offers 24/7 counseling</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723458-greymind-ais-mental-health-platform-offers-24-7-counseling</link><description><![CDATA[Patients often wait for a long time to see a mental health specialist to get the help they need, and Greymind AI’s mental health platform, Reboot AI, offers a stop-gap measure to provide structured early intervention with built-in escalation to human clinicians.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Storx sensors monitor fetal health during labor and delivery</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723457-storx-sensors-monitor-fetal-health-during-labor-and-delivery</link><description><![CDATA[Researchers from the University of California, Davis (UC-Davis) continue to assemble intellectual property in support of their development of methods and techniques which improve the accuracy of wearable sensor technologies.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aivis’ Qanti IHC uses AI to visualize biomarkers in cancer care</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723400-aivis-qanti-ihc-uses-ai-to-visualize-biomarkers-in-cancer-care</link><description><![CDATA[Lee Dae-hong founded Aivis Inc. in January 2021 as an AI-powered pathology software company, having led the development of the world’s first commercial under-display fingerprint recognition algorithm that was later incorporated into the Galaxy S10 and Galaxy A series of smartphones of Samsung Electronics Co. Ltd.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA clears Artrya’s Salix AI coronary plaque module</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723205-fda-clears-artryas-salix-ai-coronary-plaque-module</link><description><![CDATA[The U.S. FDA has cleared Artrya Ltd.’s 510(k) for its Salix coronary plaque (SCP) module that is a bolt-on module to the company’s Salix coronary anatomy platform.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI comes up with novel antibiotic structures</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723603-generative-ai-comes-up-with-novel-antibiotic-structures</link><description><![CDATA[Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology have developed a generative AI model that was able to generate novel antibiotic structures from either chemical fragments or de novo, starting from ammonia, methane, water or no starting point at all. In a study that was published online in <em>Cell</em>, the team tested two dozen of more than 10 million structures that were proposed as potential antibiotics by the model.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Signos adds AI to CGM to drive weight loss</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723195-signos-adds-ai-to-cgm-to-drive-weight-loss</link><description><![CDATA[Signos Inc. landed U.S. FDA clearance for its over-the-counter glucose monitoring system, which combines Dexcom Inc.'s non-prescription Stelo continuous glucose monitor with an AI-powered platform focused on weight management and metabolism. The sensor transmits glucose readings to a smartphone app that interprets the data, provides guidance for healthy habits and educates the user.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI comes up with novel antibiotic structures</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723536-generative-ai-comes-up-with-novel-antibiotic-structures</link><description><![CDATA[Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology have developed a generative AI model that was able to generate novel antibiotic structures from either chemical fragments or de novo, starting from ammonia, methane, water or no starting point at all. In a study that was published online in <em>Cell</em>, the team tested two dozen of more than 10 million structures that were proposed as potential antibiotics by the model.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI comes up with novel antibiotic structures</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723404-generative-ai-comes-up-with-novel-antibiotic-structures</link><description><![CDATA[Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology have developed a generative AI model that was able to generate novel antibiotic structures from either chemical fragments or de novo, starting from ammonia, methane, water or no starting point at all. In a study that was published online in <em>Cell</em>, the team tested two dozen of more than 10 million structures that were proposed as potential antibiotics by the model.]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TGA casts a baleful glance at medical scribes</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723174-tga-casts-a-baleful-glance-at-medical-scribes</link><description><![CDATA[Australia’s Therapeutic Goods Administration recently reported that it has concerns about the use of digital scribes, stating that any such software that analyzes or interprets clinical conversations may qualify as a regulated medical product.]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI presents challenges, opportunities for health tech assessments</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/723164-ai-presents-challenges-opportunities-for-health-tech-assessments</link><description><![CDATA[AI and machine learning products have proven complicated for regulatory authorities across the globe, but entities in the business of conducting health technology assessments also have their hands full according to several sources.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Research details new AI-enhanced 3D ultrasound imaging method</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722819-research-details-new-ai-enhanced-3d-ultrasound-imaging-method</link><description><![CDATA[A research team from Pusan National University has developed a novel deep learning model coined Moglo-Net, designed to enable three-dimensional reconstruction of images from hand-held ultrasound procedures.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI hacks disordered proteins</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722966-ai-hacks-disordered-proteins</link><description><![CDATA[Deep learning tools for protein design can also be used to create molecules that bind to them. Certain peptides, such as intrinsically disordered proteins (IDPs), are challenging to target due to their variable nature. However, scientists from the lab of Nobel laureate David Baker have developed a method to generate binders for IDPs by searching the world’s largest protein database with their AI-powered tool RFdiffusion.]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 5 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI hacks disordered proteins</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722872-ai-hacks-disordered-proteins</link><description><![CDATA[Deep learning tools for protein design can also be used to create molecules that bind to them. Certain peptides, such as intrinsically disordered proteins (IDPs), are challenging to target due to their variable nature. However, scientists from the lab of Nobel laureate David Baker have developed a method to generate binders for IDPs by searching the world’s largest protein database with their AI-powered tool RFdiffusion.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 4 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ultromics raises $55M for AI platform to tackle heart failure</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722561-ultromics-raises-55m-for-ai-platform-to-tackle-heart-failure</link><description><![CDATA[Ultromics Ltd. raised $55 million in a series C financing round to expand its commercial footprint across the U.S. and invest in the development of new AI modules for earlier, more accurate detection of cardiovascular disease, Ross Upton, CEO and founder of Ultromics told <em>BioWorld</em>.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI-based video biomarker developed for aortic stenosis</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722549-ai-based-video-biomarker-developed-for-aortic-stenosis</link><description><![CDATA[Researchers from the Yale University filed for protection of a multi-modal approach to predict the progression risk of a heart condition using artificial intelligence algorithms applied to cardiovascular videos.]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration’s AI action draws props from med tech</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722103-trump-administrations-ai-action-draws-props-from-med-tech</link><description><![CDATA[The Trump administration released an action plan for AI, which includes an exports program for full-stack AI in areas such as health care. The announcement drew the support of the Advanced Medical Technology Association, which described the initiative as an accelerant for the use of AI in health care and a boon to patient outcomes.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rakovina makes progress on ATR inhibitor program</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722405-rakovina-makes-progress-on-atr-inhibitor-program</link><description><![CDATA[Rakovina Therapeutics Inc. has reported progress in its AI-driven KT-5000AI program, advancing the development of precision ATR (ataxia telangiectasia and Rad3-related) inhibitors designed to disrupt the DNA damage response (DDR) pathway in cancer cells. Through its collaboration with Variational AI Inc., Rakovina has evaluated a vast chemical space of potential molecular structures using Variational’s AI Enki platform to identify novel compounds]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Carlsmed aims for $100M+ IPO</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721954-carlsmed-aims-for-100m-ipo</link><description><![CDATA[Carlsmed Inc. launched its IPO at a price of $14 to $16 per share for 6.7 million shares, which would raise just over $100.5 million at the midpoint. The spinal surgery technology company could well pull in more money, if recent history provides guidance. Most med-tech IPOs this year have settled at the upper end of their price range, with Caris Life Sciences Inc. notably raising its price twice before going public at $21, a dollar more than the top of its initial range.]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preemption of state privacy law on tap in cybersecurity hearing</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721941-preemption-of-state-privacy-law-on-tap-in-cybersecurity-hearing</link><description><![CDATA[The continuing proliferation of U.S. state privacy law drew the attention of developers of med-tech wearables for some time, but a recent Senate hearing delivered the news to Congress that a failure to preempt it will slow digital health innovation to a crawl.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consortium to find compounds for target involved in subarachnoid hemorrhage</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/722048-consortium-to-find-compounds-for-target-involved-in-subarachnoid-hemorrhage</link><description><![CDATA[Qanatpharma AG (QP), Zuse Institute Berlin (ZIB), Enamine Ltd. and Proteros biostructures GmbH have announced the launch of a research collaboration to accelerate the discovery of novel therapeutics targeting cerebral perfusion deficits associated with subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH).]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chugai and Gero partner to develop therapies for age-related diseases</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721863-chugai-and-gero-partner-to-develop-therapies-for-age-related-diseases</link><description><![CDATA[Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. and Gero Pte Ltd. have entered into a joint research and license agreement to develop novel therapies for age-related diseases. Chugai will create novel antibody-drug candidates for new drug targets discovered by Gero using its AI target discovery platform.]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 8 Jul 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Technologies core to UK NHS 10-year plan</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721649-technologies-core-to-uk-nhs-10-year-plan</link><description><![CDATA[The U.K. government revealed its much anticipated 10-year plan to get the National Health Service back on its feet and fit for the future. It is betting on five technologies – data, AI, Genomics, wearables and robotics – to drive the change needed to transform the health care system.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lunit, Microsoft to codevelop cloud-based clinical AI solutions</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721647-lunit-microsoft-to-codevelop-cloud-based-clinical-ai-solutions</link><description><![CDATA[Lunit Inc. reported a new collaboration with Microsoft Corp. July 2 to jointly develop medical AI programs accessible on Microsoft’s Azure cloud platform.]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK’s MHRA first regulatory to join Health AI’s global regulator network</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721138-uks-mhra-first-regulatory-to-join-health-ais-global-regulator-network</link><description><![CDATA[The U.K. Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency reported June 24 it joined a global regulatory network for AI that is part of the Health AI regulatory initiative &ndash; a program that will invite another nine regulatory agencies to take part in the initiative in the months ahead.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two new options presented at ADA for early diagnosis of T1D</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721219-two-new-options-presented-at-ada-for-early-diagnosis-of-t1d</link><description><![CDATA[Classically, the diagnosis of type 1 diabetes comes after a patient presents with unexplained weight loss, extreme thirst and frequent urination and a lab test reveals off-the-charts blood glucose levels. At the 85th Scientific Sessions of the American Diabetes Association in Chicago, researchers highlighted two options – a blood test and a machine learning model – for diagnosing the disease much earlier in its progression, when damage to the pancreas' beta cells could be slowed.]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deepecho secures FDA clearance for fetal imaging platform</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721206-deepecho-secures-fda-clearance-for-fetal-imaging-platform</link><description><![CDATA[Deepecho Inc. received the U.S. FDA’s nod for its AI-based platform that assesses fetal biometry and amniotic fluid volume  to improve the efficiency and precision of fetal ultrasound diagnostics.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK’s MHRA opens second round in AI airlock program</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721205-uks-mhra-opens-second-round-in-ai-airlock-program</link><description><![CDATA[The U.K. Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency opened a second round in its AI airlock program although this round, like the first round, will be limited to four applicants.]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deski raises $6M for Heartfocus cardiac imaging software</title><link>https://www.bioworld.com/articles/721151-deski-raises-6m-for-heartfocus-cardiac-imaging-software</link><description><![CDATA[Deski SAS raised $6 million in a seed round to support the launch of its cardiac imaging software, Heartfocus, in the U.S. The AI-driven heart exam tool helps health care professionals perform echocardiograms from any ultrasound probe to enable the early detection of heart disease.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>